All right, here's a short demo showing Superlogical working with remote hosts.
This is going to be a short demo, not going to dive into details of everything,
not going to explain how everything works, but I hope you enjoy it.
I hope you get an idea about how this stuff is going to look.
So first, when I start up, I'm just in my local application, local session.
Of course, even though it's local, it's persistent, so I could type,
and I could reopen the application, and that's saved.
But I could also connect to remote hosts.
We don't just want persistent sessions locally, we want them remotely.
So let me open the command palette, add a remote host, and I have some infrastructure here.
This is actually a VPS that's running remotely that's connected to my tailnet,
so I could connect to that, and we're in.
And, you know, it looks like an SSH session.
But I could open a split, and I have two now, and this is over the same connection.
And I also want to highlight that this is a real login.
So if I list my logins, this is a real thing.
Rex is the multiplexer name.
So this isn't just a terminal opening via our server.
Our server does a full SSH-style system login.
So that shows up who works, all of your login shell stuff is loaded,
all of your per-user limits are honored and respected on your Linux machine, etc., etc., etc.
This is a full login, and actually Rex is a full SSH replacement,
but I'm not going to talk too much about that here.
I actually don't have SSH on this machine at all.
This is how I get in.
But, yeah, so let's create a split.
Let's start there.
Next thing, if you look up here, the machine showed up in our session list,
and we got the new session, and every new session gets a unique name.
This is Drifting Cedar.
We could just rename it.
So I could rename this session, and then say it's the demo session.
And there you go, it's the demo.
Let's go hop back to our Mac.
So we're back on the Mac, and I want to actually go to the CLI.
So every terminal session gets this injected.
So on my local machine, I have it.
If I go back to this one, it's also installed here.
But let's go back up here.
And the first thing I want to do is actually not this.
I want to do what is it called, like whoami?
The whoami tells you who you're logged in as.
So I'm connecting, I'm on my Mac, connecting to Hill, and it's telling me who I am and how I got there.
So I connected as MitchellH at GitHub.
That's my Tailscale identity.
Since I connected over Tailscale, that's how I got my identity.
Over Tailscale via a couple hops from this machine, and I'm acting as MitchellH.
I did hint earlier that this is a full SSH replacement, so I could also log in as root.
And that's root.
Like I said, I'm not going to get into the full details of the SSH replacement thing, but there is a mapping on the server side of who can act as who and how they authenticate.
And we respect preexisting SSH keys and everything.
So this is all just working.
So I could log in as both.
But we could do some other fun stuff with the CLI that I want to show you.
So if we look, we have the demo session, right?
Okay, but here on my Mac, I could create a new session, and Crisp Sierra has showed up.
If I go there, you could see that it's empty.
It's new.
I could open a tab.
But it's clearly different from the demo where, you know, I dropped this up.
Let's just put some things in here so we could see, and let's go root.
The other thing I want you to notice is as I'm typing, it's hard to tell, of course, over video, but as I'm typing, this is really responsive.
This is a remote server that's actually across the country for me, and it feels local.
We bring in a lot of the architectural similarities as Mosh into this, and so it's going to continue to get better.
We don't do everything Mosh does, but I get asked a lot if we do some stuff, and we do.
So I'm not ready to go into details exactly of the full protocol and transport, but it's super responsive.
The other thing I want to notice is if I quit, quit my local app, it'll be a little slower to load this time, but we reconnect, and we go back into the last session we were in.
So I immediately went in, and we're still here.
And, of course, all our sessions are still here.
Next, if I grab this ID here, I could actually go ahead and do a session kill, and I want you to notice how fast this is.
So we have this here.
I'm talking to this server.
If I hit go and reopen, it's gone already.
All this stuff is super fast.
It propagates to all the clients really quickly.
And, again, this is all about bringing down the barrier so that everything feels local.
The barrier between local and remote has to disappear.
It all has to feel like it's right at your fingertips, and that's built in all the way through.
Okay, I want to show one other kind of fun feature.
So if I go over here, we added a feature where if you do Command-Shift-G, we could jump.
It's a Go to Directory feature.
So we could go ahead and jump, let's say, to the macOS folder, and it opens a new terminal in that folder.
So you could see that we're here.
Okay, makes sense, right?
Well, the cool part is if we go ahead and go over here, I'm now on my remote machine in the root directory, and I do that again.
It works.
Go to Directory works over remote connections as well.
So I could go to proc.
It lists the things in proc.
I could go to home.
We could see some users.
I could go back to Mitchell H, hit enter, and there we go.
We're in there.
Again, this is all about dropping the boundary of local versus remote.
Everything that works local should work remote.
Everything that works remote should work local.
And that permeates through everything in our design here and functionality.
The way that Go to Directory works over remote connections is really cool.
We're going to have to wait for future details of how our architecture works to enable things like this.
And we'll continue to show more functionality as we get closer.
But that's a demo of remote hosts.
Some hints towards some really cool stuff like Rex being an SSH replacement.
Some sneaky little protocol things in there for both performance and functionality.
There's a lot here.
So hope you liked that demo and talk to you soon.